<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Specs on UAPI Group Specifications</title><link>https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/</link><description>Recent content in Specs on UAPI Group Specifications</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/sysext/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/sysext/</guid><description>This content has moved to Extension Images</description></item><item><title>Base Directory Specification</title><link>https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/base_directory_specification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/base_directory_specification/</guid><description>Base Directory Specification # Introduction # Various specifications specify files and file formats. This specification defines where these files should be looked for by defining one or more base directories relative to which files should be located.
Basics # The XDG Base Directory Specification is based on the following concepts:
There is a single base directory relative to which user-specific data files should be written. This directory is defined by the environment variable $XDG_DATA_HOME.</description></item><item><title>Boot Loader Specification</title><link>https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/boot_loader_specification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/boot_loader_specification/</guid><description>The Boot Loader Specification # This document defines a set of file formats and naming conventions that allow the boot loader menu entries to be shared between multiple operating systems and boot loaders installed on one device.
Operating systems cooperatively manage boot loader menu entry directories that contain drop-in files, making multi-boot scenarios easy to support. Boot menu entries are defined via two simple formats that can be understood by different boot loader implementations, operating systems, and userspace programs.</description></item><item><title>Discoverable Disk Image</title><link>https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/discoverable_disk_image/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/discoverable_disk_image/</guid><description>Discoverable Disk Image (DDI) # DDIs (Discoverable Disk Images) are self-described file system images that follow the DPS ( Discoverable Partitions Specification), wrapped in a GPT partition table, that may contain root (or /usr/) filesystems, system extensions, configuration extensions, portable services, containers and more, and are all protected by signed dm-verity all combined into one. They are designed to be composable and stackable, and provide security by default.
Image Format # The images use the GPT partition table verbatim, so it will not be redefined here.</description></item><item><title>Discoverable Partitions Specification</title><link>https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/discoverable_partitions_specification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/discoverable_partitions_specification/</guid><description>The Discoverable Partitions Specification (DPS) # TL;DR: Let&amp;rsquo;s automatically discover, mount and enable the root partition, /home/, /srv/, /var/ and /var/tmp/ and the swap partitions based on GUID Partition Tables (GPT)!
This specification describes the use of GUID Partition Table (GPT) UUIDs to enable automatic discovery of partitions and their intended mountpoints. Traditionally Linux has made little use of partition types, mostly just defining one UUID for file system/data partitions and another one for swap partitions.</description></item><item><title>Extension Images</title><link>https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/extension_image/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/extension_image/</guid><description>Extension Images # Extension Images are DDIs ( Discoverable Disk Images) that are built to extend a base system via an overlay. A base system or a root DDI can be extended by several extension DDIs via, usually, a read-only OverlayFS. The defining characteristic of an Extension Image is that it contains an extension-release.&amp;lt;IMAGE&amp;gt; file that identifies itself and the base system or root DDI it applies to, and must not contain an os-release file.</description></item><item><title>Linux TPM PCR Registry</title><link>https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/linux_tpm_pcr_registry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/linux_tpm_pcr_registry/</guid><description>🔏 Linux TPM PCR Registry 🗒️ # TPM PCRs are a scarce resource, there are only 24 of them in typical standards compliant TPMs. According to the TCG PC Client Specific Platform Firmware Profile Specification | Trusted Computing Group PCRs 8…15 are for the OS to make use of. In this document we intend to document for Linux platforms which component is using which PCR in order to minimize conflicts.</description></item><item><title>Unified Kernel Image</title><link>https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/unified_kernel_image/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/unified_kernel_image/</guid><description>Unified Kernel Image (UKI) # A Unified Kernel Image (UKI) is a combination of an UEFI boot stub program, a Linux kernel image, an initrd, and further resources in a single UEFI PE file. This file can either be directly invoked by the UEFI firmware (which is useful in particular in some cloud/Confidential Computing environments) or through a boot loader (which is generally useful to allow multiple kernel versions with interactive or automatic selection of version to boot into).</description></item><item><title>Version Format Specification</title><link>https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/version_format_specification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://uapi-group.org/specifications/specs/version_format_specification/</guid><description>Version Format Specification # Many of the formats and concepts defined in these specifications rely on having a sort order for strings that include version components, and use it for various purposes, such as choosing the default boot entry in the Boot Loader Specification. This specification defines what format these strings must follow, and how to deterministically compare them.
Version Format # The version string is a sequence of zero or more characters.</description></item></channel></rss>